

2750 Gallows Rd Apt 434, Vienna VA, 22180

703-507-9485

 \bowtie

remo@romergarcia.com

PROFILE:

Multimedia Graphic Artist, and Visual Designer. I've been called a 5 tool player, and I think the wide spectrum of my expertise and my capability to react to all kinds of situations had made me the "go-to guy" when something unforeseen happens and needs to be done yesterday, specially when it comes to Digital Media.

QUALIFICATIONS:

Extensive knowledge of Design Theory, User Centered Design, Typography, and Color Theory. Experience working with different types and formats of graphics, in web and print media. Ability to create, enhance, and modify graphic content; Ability to create and execute concepts from start to finish. Always open to feedback; Dynamic team player: Problem solver, Fast Jearner, Fluent in Spanish.

Ratner Companies, Vienna VA

Senior Designer/Multimedia Producer (2019- Present)

Visual Designer in charge of all Digital Content for Hair Cuttery, BUBBLES salons, Salon Cielo, Cibu and Ratner Companies, such content includes video and audio assets, digital photography, graphics, QR codes, etc. Redesigned and developed ratner companies.com using WordPress as a CMS and Pantheon as hosting platform.

Ratner Companies, Vienna VA

Senior Designer (2015 - 2019)

Designer in charge of BUBBLES salons' branding and advertisement, Responsible for concepting and executing all in-salon and online advertising materials. Photographer and lighting technician on field for every photoshoot inhouse and on-location. Also responsible for photo processing, editing and retouch

Ratner Companies, Vienna VA

Digital Applications Designer (2012 - 2014)

Part of the creative department, responsible for all digital internal and external advertising pieces, such as landing pages, marketing emails, banners, website updates, etc. In addition to creating and implementing digital material, also produced traditional print media and created technology that interacted with traditional and digital media, etc. Photographer and lighting technician on field for several photo shoots on a regular basis.

EXPERIENCE:

Time Life, Fairfax VA

eCommerce Web Designer (2007 - 2012)

Only Designer in-house, responsible for all the graphics for the website, marketing emails, landing pages, print ads, inserts, and everything related with graphic design, Also worked on troubleshooting and developing web based solutions for the eCommerce team, day to day issues with platform and software.

DocHarbor, Chantilly VA

Scan operator, and Quality Control. (2006 - 2007)

Responsible for scanning, indexing, coding and reviewing personal document folders to transfer them to electronic format. Indexed and coded an average of 200 documents every hour with less than 2% errors.

Adesa Washington DC, Dulles VA.

Photographer, Digital Image Development, Digital Photo Editing (2005-2006).

Responsible for taking pictures, optimize and prepare them to be uploaded to the company's website for every online auction; and acted as a liaison between Operations, IT department and Online Sales.

2005-2007 Multimedia, ITT Technical Institute Chantilly, VA USA

Associate of Applied Science Degree, Information Technology-Multimedia.

2002-2004 Comercial Engineering, Universidad Técnica de Oruro

Facultad de Ciencias Económicas, Financieras y Administrativas Oruro-Bolivia.

Adobe Creative Suite, Digital Photography, Photo Manipulation, Photography set up and lighting, Video editing, SEO, Cross-Browser Compatibility, JavaScript & JavaScript Libraries (JQuery, Mootools), Web Graphic Optimization, Print Graphic Optimization, Web Standards, Social Media Interaction, HTML5, CSS.

SKILLS

EDUCATION: